Philip Hobsbaum collection, 1962-1971
Emory University
Philip Hobsbaum collection, 1962-1971
Hobsbaum, Philip.
Manuscript Collection No. 1013
.25 linear ft. (1 box)
Papers relating to Philip Hobsbaum, English poet, critic, and teacher, including correspondence, typescripts, and proof sheets.
Emory University Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library
Source
Purchase, unknown.
Restrictions on access
Unrestricted access.
Biographical Note
Philip Hobsbaum, poet, critic, and teacher, was born in London June 29, 1932. He attended Downing College at Cambridge, studying with F.R. Leavis. Around 1955 he began a series of writing workshops, later known as "The Group," that met in Cambridge, London, Belfast, and Glasgow. In 1959 Hobsbaum began work on a graduate degree at Sheffield University under the direction of William Empson. From 1962 to 1966 he taught at Queens University in Belfast, resigning due to the rising violence in North Ireland and the breakup of his marriage to Hannah Kelly.
Hobsbaum spent the remainder of his teaching career at the University of Glasgow. From 1966 to 1985 he was a lecturer and reader before being promoted to Professor of English Literature in 1985. He married his second wife Rosemary Philips in 1976. In addition to his teaching and writing duties, Hobsbaum began the masters program in creative writing at the University of Glasgow. He retired from teaching in 1997. He has four published collections of poetry: The Place's Fault (1964), In Retreat (1966), Coming Out Fighting (1969), and Women and Animals (1972). Hobsbaum has also published two works of literary criticism.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains material related to Philip Hobsbaum's publishing activities with The Review from 1962 to 1971. The papers include correspondence with The Review editor John Smith, typescripts and proof sheets of articles published in the periodical, a letter to the editor praising Hobsbaum's article, "Elizabethan Poetry," and four typescript poems Hobsbaum submitted to The Review for publication.
Arrangement Note
Arranged by document type.
Selected Search Terms
Topical Terms
English poetry--20th century.; Poets, English--20th century.
Form/Genre Terms
Poetry.
Occupation
Poet.
Container List
- Correspondence
- Hobsbaum to John Smith, February 1962-April 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Articles
- “Elizabethan Poetry,” uncorrected TS (Box 1, Folder 2)
- “Elizabethan Poetry,” uncorrected proof (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letter to the Editor from David W. Lindsay concerning “Elizabethan Poetry” (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Poetry
- “Household Gods,” uncorrected TS, [1962?] (Box 1, Folder 5)
- “Live? Our Pupils, etc.,” uncorrected TS, [1962?] (Box 1, Folder 6)
- “Room for Development,” corrected TS, [1963?] (Box 1, Folder 7)
- “This Small Hostility,” uncorrected TS, [1962?] (Box 1, Folder 8)